In this lecture, we're going to learn about AWS services to secure AI systems.
So we'll start with Amazon Macy and AWS private link.
So Amazon Macy is a security service that uses machine learning and pattern matching
to discover and protect your sensitive data.
That sensitive data can include personally identifiable information, PI data,
such as the name of the person, address, credit card details, and many other attributes.
Now, remember from the exam perspective, Amazon Macy only works the sensitive data that you
have within an S3 bucket. So it will scan through the S3 bucket and identify
any PI information. And if it finds any PI information, then it's going to send a notification
to event bridge. And event bridge, you can think of an event bus which will get notifications
from services such as Amazon Macy and other AWS services. And it's going to invoke some downstream
AWS services such as AWS Lambda function. And let's say it's find some PI information in the S3 bucket.
It will invoke the Lambda function, which can then delete or redact that data. And it can also
send these findings to security hub. It's just an security aggregation service.
And from the exam perspective, just remember, if it's talking about S3 bucket, PI information,
then the service that is going to be used will be Amazon Macy. Okay, next, we have AWS private
link and AWS private link provides private connectivity without exposing your traffic to public
internet. And what are the benefits of that? So if the network traffic uses private link,
it doesn't travel our public internet, which reduces the risk of external threats,
such as brute force and DDOS attacks. So in summary, if you want to reduce the security threats
rather than going over the public internet, you can use AWS private link, which is a private network
from AWS. Now let's understand in which scenarios you can send traffic over the private link.
So the first one is between different AWS services between different virtual private clouds
in different AWS accounts. And then finally, between on-premise network and AWS services,
we'll also use AWS direct, correct, in that scenario. Okay, now let's understand these three
scenarios in more detail. Now let's say you are running a web application and you have a web
server that's hosted on EC2 instance. Let's say it's www.amazon.com. And then you also have some
images which are uploaded on the Amazon S3 bucket. And you can see some of the images here.
So now let's say we have a business user who's trying to access this web server www.amazon.com.
And now it makes a request to this web server asking for the photograph of an elephant.
And we know that this elephant is stored in the S3 bucket. So now this EC2 instance will make
a request to Amazon S3 bucket to fetch this elephant. So it has two options either it can go over
the public internet or it can go over AWS private link. And this is the scenario. Now you might
just say that both EC2 instance and S3 bucket are within AWS cloud. So why do we need an
AWS private link or public internet? Please note that some of the services like EC2 instance,
RDS database are hosted within the customer VPC, but some of the other services like DynamoDB,
Amazon S3 cloud watch, et cetera, they are hosted in AWS managed VPC and account.
So that's the reason why you either need an public internet or an AWS private link to access these
services. Okay, now let's take a look at all these three scenarios AWS services VPCs and
on-premise networks. So here's a chart from AWS which described this. Let's say we have an EC2
instance in a customer VPC that is in your VPC and within your account. And then as I said,
there are services from AWS which are hosted in AWS account and VPC. So you have a cloud watch
API gateway lambda S3 bucket that are hosted in AWS account and VPC. Now if this EC2 wants to access
any of these services, then it has to go over the private link or public internet. Then similarly,
let's say another scenario where you are accessing some data from another organization which is your
partner organization and they have an EC2 instance in their AWS account and VPC and you have your
EC2 instance in your account and VPC. So how you can access them is either through public internet
or through the AWS private link and that's the connectivity is showing. Now the third scenario we
had discussed where somebody from the on-premise wants to access let's say this S3 bucket and it also
has an AWS account and here is the VPC from the AWS account. So how that traffic would be
routed is from the on-premise data center it will use AWS direct connect and AWS direct
connect you can think of a dedicated network cable to connect your data center to a AWS account.
It will go where it will direct connect to your account and then from your AWS account it will be
routed by a private link to S3. Now from an example perspective there are a couple of important
things you need to know which is gateway endpoint and interface endpoint. So what's a gateway endpoint?
So gateway endpoint is just an IP address that you create within your AWS account and VPC.
Then let's say this EC2 instance wants to access data in Amazon S3 bucket. So it is going to
route all the traffic to this IP address called as gateway endpoint and then from gateway endpoint
the traffic be routed to Amazon S3 using this AWS private link. Similarly interface endpoint
does the same thing. So you will just have an IP address and this traffic could be routed to this
IP address and then via AWS private link it will route that request. So remember that while
as it was private link is a private connectivity but you cannot use it directly. So you will have
to create either a gateway endpoint or an interface endpoint and then route the traffic via
AWS private link. And what's the difference between gateway endpoint and interface endpoint and as we
discussed in this lecture there are a lot of AWS services that are hosted in an AWS managed VPC
and account like S3, Lambda, APA gateway, CloudWatch and so on. Now if you want to access
over AWS private link Amazon S3 or DynamoDB then you use gateway endpoints but if you want to use
any other service other than S3 and DynamoDB then you use interface endpoints.
So hopefully it's clear just remember one last thing that let's say we have EC2 or RDS which is a
database from AWS. Those are some of the services that are deployed within your own VPC. So you don't
need the AWS private link or interface or gateway endpoint. This only required for services that
are hosted in the AWS VPC and account. Okay that's pretty much it from this lecture I'll
in the next lecture. Thank you.